Hey guys, welcome to another video, this very short video, it will be like two to three minutes.
So in this video, we are going to discuss about the two kind of access tokens, so we already
said it's a primary and important nation token, so there's a difference between both
of this, we all know what is a process and what is a thread, so the process is a container
and a thread is a execution object of a program, let me open up CMD here, so if you open a CMD,
I already said the windows of the register will allocate access token for me and I can use this access
token anywhere, so if I need to search any resource or if I need to go to another location or
if I need to load any other executable from the CMD, I can use the same access token,
so there's a token of access token on a primary and on another one is a impulse nation,
the primary access token will be used by the process, okay, so if I open a CMD.exe,
there will be a primary access token, it will be used by the process and we all know this,
let me open up the machine and let me open a CMD here, I have a process hacker, so I can
explain it better, so here is a normal user access token will be there, if I open up process hacker,
let me go to the CMD and this entire CMD process has a primary access token, the primary
access token is basically used to buy the process, so another one is an impulse nation access token
that was used to buy the threat, okay, so I had said the threat distribution object of the program,
the process contain more than one threat or no more than a threat, so a threat will be using
a impulse nation token, so where this threat getting the impulse nation token, okay,
it's a simple one, the threat will be getting the impulse nation token from primary token,
okay, so let's say the CMD.exe needs to access one file from the directory, so it will be using
the access token, the primary access token, so whether this user has a privilege to access
that file inside the directory, so this process will be using the primary token, so also we have
an set of threat, okay, so here you can see there's only one threat was running,
but some other process will be running multiple threats more than 50, 60 threats, so at that time,
if a threat, if any of the threat needs to access any resource or any files inside the
inside any of the directory in windows, so now the threats, the threat will be
impersonating a primary token from the process and it will be using
temporarily to access that resource, okay, the impulse nation token or
temporarily given by the primary token, so the process will be giving your
temp access token to the threat, that's called as an impulse nation token, it will be taking a primary
token, as an impersonate mode, and it will be using to access the files and resource inside the
windows operating system, so in the overall scenario, the process will be using the primary access
token, the threat will be using the impulse nation access token, the impulse nation access token will
be coming from the primary access token, so that's why we are saying impulse nation, impulse
native primary access token, it's called the same post nation, so both of the tokens will be used
to access resource or do anything or open any files or allocate system, a certain privilege for
incident machine, okay, so that's all about the video, in the next video we'll be developing the
code and we'll be doing a access token manipulation attack, yeah, this is how both and we'll see you
guys in the next video, bye bye.